Guide to the Richard Henry Pratt Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Richard Henry Pratt papers
1862-1972
WA MSS S-1174
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
23.18
(102 boxes) + 3 broadsides
The collection includes letter-press books, writings, diaries, notes, photographs, and drawings. The papers largely relate to Pratt's work with and theories on the education of American Indians and his involvement with the Carlisle Indian School. Included is material relating to the controversies surrounding his work and much relating to Indians and Indian life in general. There are a group of Indian photographs and drawings, and papers relating to members of Pratt's family.
Pratt, Richard Henry, 1840-1924
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Richard Henry Pratt Papers were the gift of Margaret Hawkins Seelye, Edgar M. Hawkins, Jr., and Richard Pratt Hawkins, 1959 and 1976.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 34, 42, and 43: ‡a Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
RICHARD HENRY PRATT (1840-1924)
Richard Henry Pratt was a soldier in the American Civil War and later fought in armed conflicts with Native Americans on the frontier.
It was Pratt's belief that the Native American should receive an American education and be absorbed into American society. Pratt gained support for this view when he commanded a group of seventy-two Native American prisoners at St. Augustine, Florida, in 1875. Through education and humane treatment, Pratt believed that even the most "savage" of Native Americans might become educated and law abiding citizens of the United States.
Pratt's efforts resulted in the founding of the Carlisle Indian Industrial School at Carlisle, Pennsylvania, in 1879. As head of the school, Pratt stressed both academic and industrial education. He believed that if the Native American was to claim his rightful place as an American citizen, he must renounce his tribal way of life, abandon the reservation, and seek education and employment among the "best classes" of Americans.
During his superintendency of the Carlisle School, Pratt became an outspoken opponent of tribal segregation on reservations. He believed that this system as administered and encouraged by the Indian Bureau was hindering the education and civilization of the Native American and creating helpless wards of the state. These views inevitably led to conflicts with the Indian Bureau and the government officials who supported the reservation system. Long standing animosities came to a head in May of 1904 when Pratt strongly denounced the Indian Bureau and the reservation system as a hindrance to the civilization and assimilation of the Native American. This controversy, coupled with earlier disputes with the government over civil service reform, led to Pratt's forced retirement as superintendent of the Carlisle School in 1904. This did not, however, end Pratt's long career as a crusader for Native American causes. A tireless speaker and letter writer, he waged a vigorous campaign for the fair and humane treatment of Native Americans until his death in 1924.
Scope and Contents
The papers span Richard Henry Pratt's long career as an Army officer, educator, and advocate for Native American causes.
The papers are divided into seven series. Series I, General Correspondence and Official Papers consists of official Army papers as well as Pratt's incoming and outgoing letters. Pratt made copies of most of his letters. These copies, either carbons, drafts, or volumes of letterpress impressions, are filed chronologically as Outgoing Letters and provide a very complete record of his letter writing. Incoming Letters are arranged alphabetically by author.
The main subject of Pratt's correspondence until 1904 was the founding and administration of the Carlisle Indian Industrial School. This correspondence reveals Pratt's efforts to gain support for the school from Indians, the government, and private donors as well as the day to day difficulties in the actual management of the school. In addition, there is correspondence with former Indian students and Carlisle staff members, including Howard E. Gansworth, Dr. Carlos Montezuma, and Chauncey Yellow Robe, on the position and problems of Indians in America.
Pratt corresponded with many prominent Americans interested in the plight of Native Americans. These correspondents include: Lyman Abbott (10 items), Samuel C. Armstrong (101 items), Spencer F. Baird (21 items), Rudolph Blankenburg (14 items), James W. Champney (18 items), Clara B. Colby (2 items), Henry L. Dawes (31 items), W. Maslin Frysinger (22 items), Henry G. Ganns (39 items), Howard E. Gansworth (22 items), Franklin K. Lane (18 items), John D. Miles (145 items), Carlos Montezuma (122 items), Knute Nelson (34 items), Arthur C. Parker (45 items), Carl Schurz (12 items), and Cato Sells (13 items).
Official Papers contains material on Pratt's early Army career and his experiences with Native American prisoners at St. Augustine. This section contains reports, orders, official correspondence and communications. Information about Pratt's early experiments with Native American education and on the establishment of the Carlisle School may also be found here.
Series II, Family Correspondence, contains Pratt's letters to and from members of his family. Also included in this series is the correspondence of his daughter, Nana Pratt Hawkins; his wife, Anna Laura Pratt; his son, Mason Delano Pratt; his grandson, R. H. Pratt, II; his granddaughter, Sarah Pratt; his son-in-law, Guy LeRoy Stevick; and his daughter, Marion Pratt Stevick. Of special interest is Pratt's correspondence with his wife about his experiences with Indians while serving in the Army and about the founding of the Carlisle School. The correspondence of Pratt's children details their futile efforts to have Pratt's autobiographical work published after his death. Correspondence between Pratt's children and Elaine Goodale Eastman, author of Pratt: The Red Man's Moses, reveal the preparation of and reaction to this biography.
The correspondence of Mason D. Pratt offers some insight into Pratt's experiences at St. Augustine, Florida. Details about Pratt's role in the Sioux Commission of 1888 are found in the correspondence of his son-in-law, Guy LeRoy Stevick.
Series III, Addresses, Diaries, Writings, and Notes, contains copies of articles and addresses by Pratt which provide a good source for Pratt's beliefs on Native American education and civilization. In addition, there are several versions of Pratt's autobiographical work and also four diaries which recount Pratt's activities during the Civil War.
Series IV, Photographs and Drawings, contains numerous photographs of the facilities and students of the Carlisle Indian Industrial School. There are also a large number of photographs of Pratt. Other subjects include the Native American prisoners of St. Augustine and Fort Marion, their place of confinement. Of special interest are the "before and after" pictures of many Indians that contrast their "savage" appearance upon arrival at the Carlisle School with the "civilized" appearance after receiving the benefits of an education. There are negatives for many of the photographs in this series. Contact prints have been made for the glass plate negatives, and the originals have been placed in Restricted Fragile, where they may be consulted only with the approval of the appropriate curator.
This series also includes many drawings made by Native Americans at St. Augustine and Carlisle. These drawings are of interest not only because of their artistic merit, but because of what they reveal about the Indian's way of life and their perception of the changing world. A series of drawings by a Kiowa Indian, Etahdleuh Doanmoe, relate in pictorial form his journey from the plains to imprisonment in St. Augustine and his experiences in captivity.
Series V, Clippings, Scrapbooks, and Miscellaneous Publications, contains a large amount of newspaper clippings, both loose and in scrapbooks, that chronicle Pratt's activities from the St. Augustine days to the end of his career. Two scrapbooks in this series are devoted to press reactions to the Sioux Commission of 1888 of which Pratt was a member.
Series VI, Special Files, contains assorted biographical materials about Pratt and miscellaneous materials on the Carlisle Indian Industrial School.
Series VII, December 1976 Acquisition, contains printed material, ephemera, and photographs pertaining to Pratt and the Carlisle School; material concerning Pratt's service in the United States Army; genealogical materials pertaining to Pratt; correspondence; photographs and negatives of Native American camps, the Pratt family, and trips to Alaska and New Mexico; sea beans polished by Native American prisoners at Fort Marion, Florida; and maps showing Indian reservations within the United States.
Arrangement
Organized into seven series: I. General Correspondence and Official Papers, 1867-1924. II. Family Correspondence, 1862-1956. III. Addresses, Diaries, Writings, and Notes, 1862-1953. IV. Photographs and Drawings, 1875-1904. V. Clippings and Miscellaneous Publications, 1874-1953. VI. Special Files, 1878-1963. VII. December 1976 Acquisition, 1871-1972.
Indians of North America -- Education; Indians of North America -- Government relations; Soldiers -- United States; Teachers -- Pennsylvania; Indians of North America -- Pictorial works; Off-reservation boarding schools -- United States; Indian students -- United States; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States -- Maps -- 19th century; Diaries -- United States -- 19th century; Drawings (visual works) -- United States -- 19th century; Ledger drawings -- United States -- 19th century; Photographic prints -- United States -- 19th century; Glass negatives -- United States; Maps (documents) -- United States -- 19th century; Soldiers -- United States -- 19th century; Teachers -- Pennsylvania -- 19th century; Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922; Armstrong, S. C. (Samuel Chapman), 1839-1893; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887; Dawes, Henry L. (Henry Laurens), 1816-1903; Doanmoe, Etahdleuh, 1856-1888; Gates, Merrill Edwards, 1848-1922; Harris, William Torrey, 1835-1909; Hyde, Alexander; Jackson, Sheldon, 1834-1909; Montezuma, Carlos, 1866-1923; Ohetoint, Charles; Parker, Arthur Caswell, 1881-1955; Pratt, Richard Henry, 1840-1924; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; United States Indian School (Carlisle, Pa.)
- General Correspondence and Official Papers, 1867-1924; Series I; (74 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, General Correspondence and Official Papers is divided into four subseries. Incoming Letters received by Pratt are arranged alphabetically by author and chronologically within each folder. A folder of unidentified material is placed at the end of this section. Outgoing Letters written by Pratt are arranged chronologically. Pratt's letters from the years 1872 to 1904 are bound in 60 volumes of letterpress copies. Additional unbound letters from these years, as well as the letters from 1904 until Pratt's death in 1924, are arranged chronologically in folders. Letters of Others, found with Pratt's or Pratt's family's correspondence, but which are not to or from Pratt are arranged alphabetically by author. Official Papers is a file of material relating to Pratt's early Army career, his command of Indian prisoners in Florida, the beginnings of the Carlisle Indian Industrial School, and other Army related matters. Reports, orders, official correspondence and communications are contained in this section. This file contains material both to and from Pratt as well as communications of others. The material in this file is arranged chronologically. Note: Individuals represented in Official Papers may also be represented in other subseries of General Correspondence.
  - INCOMING LETTERS
    - "Ab-Ah" general, 13 items, 1896-1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Am-At" general, 16 items, 1888-1920, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Abbott, Austin, 1 item, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Abbott, Ernest H.
      See: The Outlook Company
    - Abbott, Harriet F., 2 items, 1894-95
    - Abbott, Lyman, 10 items, 1885-1917 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Abbott, Willis J.
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: The Christian Science Monitor, Box 29, folder 810
    - Agnew, Edith, 1 item, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Agnew, Mary N., 4 items, 1901-08
    - Ailes, Milton E.
      See: National Republican Congressional Committee, Box 7, folder 229
    - Alden, Henry M., 1 item, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alger, Russell A., 1 item, 1898
    - Allen, Edgar A., 6 items, 1904-23 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Allison, William B., 4 items, 1880-94, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Alvord, Henry E., 2 items, 1887
    - American Peace Society, 6 items, 1921-23 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Armstrong, R. F., 7 items, 1900-01 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Armstrong, Samuel C., 14 items, 1877-78 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Armstrong, Samuel C., 17 items, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Armstrong, Samuel C., 23 items, 1880-81 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Armstrong, Samuel C., 17 items, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Armstrong, Samuel C., 14 items, 1883-86 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Armstrong, Samuel C., 16 items, 1887-91, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Astor, C. A., 6 items, 1886, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Astor, [John J.?], 2 items, 1888
    - Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railway Co., 3 items, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Atherton, George W., 1 item, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Avery, R. B., 4 items, 1884
    - "Ba" general, 9 items, 1891-1923, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Be" general, 16 items, 1884-1921 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Bi-Brown" general, 22 items, 1879-1922 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "Bruce-Bu" general, 11 items, 1901-20 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Baird, Spencer F., 21 items, 1877-82 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bakeless, O. H., 2 items, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Baker, Newton D., 3 items, 1917-18 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Ballinger, Richard A., 1 item, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bank of Italy, 5 items, 1920
    - Bard, Thomas R., 1 item, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Barrows, John H., 1 item, 1900
    - Beattie, W. G.
      See: Edward Marsden, Box 6, folder 192
    - Belt, R. V., 7 items, 1890-95 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Beltzhoover, Frank E., 1 item, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Biddle, Edward W., 14 items, 1905-20
    - Bishop, Thomas G., 3 items, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Blaine, James G., 1 item, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Blankenburg, Rudolph, 14 items, 1900-11, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Bliss, Cornelius, 1 item, 1898
    - Boas, Franz, 1 item, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Bond, The Rev. H. F., 1 item, 1887
    - Bonnin, Gertrude S., 4 items, 1909-19 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Bourassa, Rosa, 2 items, 1899, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Bourke, John G., 2 items, 1886
    - Bowersox, Katherine S., 4 items, 1902, 1920
    - Briggs, Hannah E., 5 items, 1878-79 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Bright, Marshall H., 3 items, 1903
    - Brosius, S. M., 2 items, 1914, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Brown, Elmer E., 3 items, 1913, 1915
    - Brown, John B., 8 items, 1901-21 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Browning, D. M., 6 items, 1893, 1895
    - Brunot, Felix R., 6 items, 1882-83 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Buchanan, William I., 2 items, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Buck, Charles W., 4 items, 1914-15
    - Buck, Spyna D., 1 item, 1920
    - Burdette, Robert J., 1 item, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Burgess, Marianna, 10 items, 1879-1921
    - Burke, Charles H., 6 items, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Butler, Nicholas M., 1 item, 1922
    - "Ca" general, 10 items, 1878-1920 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - "Ch-Cl" general, 13 items, 1888-1923 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "Co" general, 17 items, 1878-1923 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "Cr-Cu" general, 11 items, 1879-1923 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Call, Wilkinson, 1 item, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Camp, Walter, 1 item, 1918
    - Campbell, Philip P., 2 items, 1919-21
    - Campbell, W. P., 3 items, 1903-1905, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Carlisle Students, 1 item, 1886
    - Carrington, Henry B., 1 item, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Carter, Charles D., 9 items, 1912-1920 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Caruthers, H., 2 items, 1877-78 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Caruthers, Paul, 1 item, 1879
    - Caswell, Benjamin, 2 items, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Chalcraft, Edwin L., 17 items, 1903-1917 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Chamberlain, George E., 1 item, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Champney, James W. and Elizabeth W., 18 items, 1878-1902, n.d.
    - Chandler, Harry, 7 items, 1921-24 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Church, William C., 2 items, 1894, 1906
    - Clapp, Moses E., 1 item, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Clark, Charles H., 1 item, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Claxton, P. P., 3 items, 1915-19
    - Colby, Clara B., 2 items, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Collier, Robert, 9 items, 1911-21 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Collins, Ellen, 3 items, 1888-94, n.d.
    - Collier's
      See: John M. Oskison, Box 7, folder 236
    - Condit, The Rev. James
    - Conger, Omar D., 1 item, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Coolidge, Sherman, 3 items, 1913, 1920
    - Corbin, H. C., 4 items, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Corrington, J. A., 1 item, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Council, W. H., 9 items, 1901-02, 1904
    - Cunningham, Magistrate
      See: White Buffalo, Box 9, folder 326
    - Curtis, Charles, 3 items, 1916, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Cutcheon, Byron M., 11 items, 1885-1903
    - Cutter, Emma A., 3 items, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - "Da-De" general, 19 items, 1890-1923, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - "Di-Du" general, 19 items, 1876-1921 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Dagenett, Charles E., 4 items, 1908-22 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Davis, A. J., 1 item, 1885
    - Davis, George W., 3 items, 1894-95 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Davis, O. DeForest, 1 item, 1920
    - Davis, Richard, 10 items, 1890-96 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Dawes, Anna L., 15 items, 1885-1922 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Dawes, Electra A., 2 items, 1892, 1894
    - Dawes, Henry L., 13 items, 1882, 1884-89 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Dawes, Henry L., 18 items, 1892-1901 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Deems, Charles F., 1 item, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Denny, Nellie R., 15 items, 1908-21
    - Dent, Frederick J., 1 item, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - DePoe, Robert R., 6 items, 1914
    - Devins, John B., 4 items, 1903-04 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Dharmapala, A. H., 2 items, 1902
    - Dixon, C. R., 1 item, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Dodds, Alexander, 4 items, 1913-14
    - Dixon, The Rev. John
    - Dodge, D. Stuart, 2 items, 1883, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Dodge, Grace H., n.d.
    - Dodge, Mary M., 2 items, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Dodge, Melissa P., 1 item, 1883
    - Dodge, William Earl, 1 item, 1881 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Dodge, William Earl, Jr., 5 items, 1883, 1885
    - Dorsey, The Rev. James O., 2 items, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Douglass, Frederick and Helen, 2 items, 1893, 1899
    - Draper, Andrew S., 8 items, 1891-1905 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Drum, R. C., 4 items, 1875-98, n.d.
    - Dubois, W. E. B., 1 item, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - "E" general, 4 items, 1883-1918 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Eastman, Charles A., 4 items, 1895-1911 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Eastman, Elaine (Goodale), 5 items, 1890-1918
    - Eaton, John, 18 items, 1881-1904 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Edmunds, George F., 1 item, 1884 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Edwards, Clarence R., 1 item, 1902
    - Edwards, Mary H., 1 item, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Eells, Edwin, 3 items, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Elkins, Stephen Benton, 1 item, 1902
    - Elms, Elsie L. and Horton G., 5 items, 1909-22 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Embrick, Milton A., 5 items, 1903-20, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Emory, C. D., 2 items, 1875, n.d.
    - "Fa-Fi" general, 13 items, 1882-1921, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - "Fl-Fr" general, 14 items, 1878-1921, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Fess, Simeon D., 6 items, 1918-22 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Field, Henry M., 3 items, 1895-99
    - Fisk, Clinton B., 1 item, 1886 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Flynn, Dennis T., 3 items, 1902-03 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Foraker, Joseph B., 1 item, 1907
    - Foster, E. C.
    - Foster, Emory
    - Francis, John, Jr., 14 items, 1917-23 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Frysinger, W. Maslin, 22 items, 1896-1923 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - "Ga-Gl" general, 12 items, 1878-1923 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - "Go-Gr" general, 13 items, 1886-1921, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Ganns, Henry G., 18 items, 1892-1901 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Ganns, Henry G., 21 items, 1902-1910 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Gansworth, Edith S. and Howard E., 22 items, 1897-1923, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Gansworth, Leander N., 6 items, 1914-21 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Garfield, James R., 1 item, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Garrett, Philip C., 12 items, 1884-94, n.d.
    - Gates, Merrill E., 11 items, 1885-94 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Gates, Merrill E., 21 items, 1899-1909 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Gibbon, John, 1 item, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Gill, Wilson L., 3 items, 1902
    - Given, James B., 1 item, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Given, Joshua, 3 items, 1888
    - Goode, George B., 2 items, 1892-93 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Gordon, Jane, 2 items, 1920
    - Gordon, John B., 3 items, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Gordon, Philip, 2 items, 1917
    - Graham, Olive
      See: Mary Morris, Box 7, folder 225
    - Grant, Frederick D., 2 items, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Grant, U. S. and other Indians, 3 items, 1918
    - Greene, Francis V., 1 item, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Griffith, William M., 3 items, 1896-97
    - Grinnell, Elizabeth, 3 items, 1892-98 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Gross, R. J., 2 items, 1904-05
    - "Ha" general, 19 items, 1902-21, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - "He-Hu" general, 19 items, 1875-1920, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Hailmann, William N., 7 items, 1894-96 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Hale, Edward Everett, 3 items, 1893-1897
    - Hall, The Rev. and Mrs. C. L., 7 items, 1878-95, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Hall, Frederick P., 5 items, 1903-20
    - Hall, Harwood, 8 items, 1900-21 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Hamilton Library Assoc., 1 item, 1919
    - Harding, Warren G., 5 items, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Hare, William H., 3 items, 1879, 1906, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Harper, J. C., 3 items, 1923
    - Harris, William Torrey, 8 items, 1898, 1901-04 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Harrison, Benjamin, 1 item, 1884 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Hartzell, Joseph C., 2 items, 1902
    - Hastings, Daniel H., 5 items, 1896-97 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Hastings, William W., 2 items, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Hawley, Joseph R., 8 items, 1881-1905
    - Haworth, J. M., 1 item, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Hayt, Ezra A., 9 items, 1878-80, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Hazen, [William Babcock], 3 items, 1875-79
    - Henderson, J. Webster, 4 items, 1919-20 (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Henderson, R. M., 5 items, 1884-1905
    - Higgins, William R., 10 items, 1859-81 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Hilles, V. S., 5 items, 1895-96
    - Himes, Charles F., 1 item, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Hitchcock, Ethan Allen, 3 items, 1899-1904
    - Hoar, George F., 1 item, 1882 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - Hooker, Charles E., 1 item, 1903
    - Hopkins, G. S., 1 item, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Howard, Oliver Otis, 8 items, 1890-1904
    - Howling Wolf, 2 items, 1879, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Hunt, Lydia L., 1 item, 1879
    - Hyde, Alexander, 17 items, 1879-80 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Interior, U.S. Dept. of, Office of Indian Affairs, Commissioner
      See: name of commissioner
    - Interior, U.S. Dept. of, Secretary
      See: name of secretary